Task number 36.
To solve this task, it is useful to
read the pages in the lecture slides
from page 30 to about page 38.
because here in the lecture, it
is showing you Haskell functions.
and how to express them in Prolog.
So, here we have this Haskell
function. And it takes two arguments:
one of these arguments... the
first one is always a list.
So, here you know it is a
list because it's obvious.
and here you know because we have this operator.
And how do you know that ys is also a list?
Well... you look here and
you see that inside this
line here, in the function, you
have f that takes ys and then xs.
And if you look again at the definition,
the first argument is always a list.
So, this means ys is also a list.
Please pay attention because the
task is telling us not to guess.
The task wants us to convert these functions...
this function from Haskell to Prolog depending
on the lecture slides that I just showed you.
So, I'm going to use this file as a draft.
And first, I'm going to write the steps
of how to convert from Haskell to Prolog,
and then I'm going to leave only the
end result and turn everything else
into comments just like these here are comments.
So, let's start with the first line. Here, we
give f an empty list and some other list,
and we get the second list as it is.
So, this becomes this. And then finally, we
write it like this. And now it's Prolog.
So, this step here in between is just
for us to understand what we're doing.
This here is not Prolog, is not Haskell. It's
nothing; it's hybrid (something in between).
Now, let's do this line.
So, here we have two lists and the first element
of the first list is x. And this is what we get.
We get a list which has the first element x
and the tail of the list is the result of
the application of f on these two lists.
As you can see, they have been swapped.
So, ys is now the first list and xs, which
used to be the tail of the first list,
is now the second list.
Now, let's refine it a little bit. So,
we say this line here becomes like this.
So, we have the first list as it is, the
second list as it is, and this is the third
parameter of f.
So, now f is looking more like Prolog code. And I
put commas in between. Okay, now, let's continue.
So, this line becomes like this.
So, what I did is capitalize
the first letter of each variable's name
because this is how you do it in Prolog.
We have capital letters here. And instead
of having the third parameter like this,
I substituted it with a list that starts
with x and ends with zs (zees) or zs (zeds).
And then I said zs is the result of the application
of f on ys and xs. And of course, as you can see,
there's no such thing in Haskell
nor in Prolog. So, this is
in between. This is hybrid
just like this line here.
And now let's go full Prolog.
So, this line becomes this line.
Now, this means the final result is
going to be this line and this line.
Now, let's turn everything into a
comment and keep the end result.
And that should be it. Now, let's test it.